<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>RabbitMQ Cookbook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014-01-07-rabbitmq-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014-01-07-rabbitmq-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;{% img left /images/rabbitmq_cookbook.jpg 200 %}
I recently finished my first go at being a technical reviewer for a technology book: the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/1b2OwRo&#34;&gt;RabbitMQ Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;. I kind of &amp;lsquo;happened&amp;rsquo; into reviewing from some of the tech talks, blog posts and &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/switchspan/rabbitmq-and-easynetq&#34;&gt;slide decks&lt;/a&gt; I have done on the subject of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rabbitmq.com/&#34;&gt;RabbitMQ&lt;/a&gt;. An editorial representative from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/&#34;&gt;Packt Publishing&lt;/a&gt; contacted me to see if I would be interested in being a technical reviewer for the upcoming book &amp;ndash; and the adventure began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A technical reviewer looks primarily at the technical correctness and ease of understanding in each of the chapters. There are plenty of opportunities to offer suggestions for improvements to the author(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-reviewing:387fd69b3fec7d6d8ae080b51a91f96e&#34;&gt;Technical Reviewing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book:387fd69b3fec7d6d8ae080b51a91f96e&#34;&gt;The Book&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is an excellent resource for anyone looking to use RabbitMQ (or any other AMQP server for that matter&amp;hellip;) for queuing/integration. Most modern software components &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Message_passing&#34;&gt;pass messages&lt;/a&gt; to other components, not data. I thoroughly enjoyed reviewing this book and learn some new RabbitMQ tricks in the process. The format uses a clean cookbook of recipe description, how to implement the recipe, and how the recipe works. It makes finding a solution to a queuing challenge a quick and easy process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book comprises over 265 pages and 70 recipes for a myriad of integration solutions. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/authors/profiles/sigismondo-boschi&#34;&gt;Sigismondo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.indigenidigitali.com/tag/gabriele-santomaggio/&#34;&gt;Gabriele&lt;/a&gt; did a great job of showing code examples for Java, C#, Ruby as well as others languages. In addition to the examples, they also show how to properly manage a RabbitMQ server and deploy it to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a brief table of contents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. Working with AMQP
2. Going beyond the AMQP Standard
3. Managing RabbitMQ
4. Mixing Different Technologies
5. Using RabbitMQ in Web Applications
6. Developing Scalable Applications
7. Developing High-Availability Applications
8. Performance Tuning for RabbitMQ
9. Extending RabbitMQ Functionality
10. RabbitMQ on AWS
11. AMQP and Cloud Computing - RabbitMQ on PAAS
12. Managing RabbitMQ Error Conditions
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite recipes in the book is for auto scaling RabbitMQ servers on AWS &amp;ndash; it is a formula you can use for not only RabbitMQ but other EC2 instances on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:387fd69b3fec7d6d8ae080b51a91f96e&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a flexible/scalable backbone for your Enterprise application (or future Enterprise application) &amp;ndash; RabbitMQ is a great option, and this book is a great head start for that option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical reviewing is also a great way to get involved with a technology that you like!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>