<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>From WordPress to Octopress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-06-02-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-06-02-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/wordpress_to_octopress.png 440 &amp;lsquo;Wordpress to Octopress&amp;rsquo; %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may or may not have noticed this blog has switched from a
hosted &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordpress.org&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; blog to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; blog.
I originally started looking at migrating the blog for a couple of
reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love ruby and I wanted to play around with &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jekyll can be deployed easily to &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github Pages is free (as in like free beer&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The amount of comment spam I am getting on WordPress was driving me
crazy (yes I know I can use Akismet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to customize my blog a little more than what is allowed
with WordPress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-initial-search:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;The initial search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially I started looking at some of the blogging tools that my
friends at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://757rb.org&#34;&gt;Hampton Roads Ruby Users Group&lt;/a&gt; where using.
The first one I came across that caught my interest was &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/metaskills&#34;&gt;Ken Collins&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://metaskills.net&#34;&gt;metaskills.net&lt;/a&gt;.
The metaskills blog uses a modified version of Jekyll which Ken has added in a few items to organize and publish easier.
You can check out his code &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/metaskills/metaskills.net&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-draft-jekyll:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;First draft: Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/octojekyll.png 200 &amp;lsquo;OctoJekyll&amp;rsquo; %}
I started out creating a plain Jekyll blog and looking at how the static
site generation worked.
There are plenty of resources on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll site&lt;/a&gt; which can show you how to install Jekyll and get it running.
You will need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-lang.org&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rubygems.org&#34;&gt;RubyGems&lt;/a&gt;.
If you are dabbling in Ruby or Rails, you will already have both of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;second-draft-jekyll-bootstrap:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;Second draft: Jekyll Bootstrap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img left /images/Jekyll-bootstrap-screen.png 300 &amp;lsquo;Jekyll Bootstrap Getting Started screen&amp;rsquo; %}
While I found Jekyll pretty cool, I wanted my site to have a little bit
of styling.
Not being a graphic designer of any sort, I started looking for some
themes that I could use to modify.
After doing a little digging on Google for Jekyll themes, I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllbootstrap.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; by
X. Note: There is also another spin off from this project called
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ruhoh.com&#34;&gt;Ruhoh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-draft-octopress:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;Final draft: Octopress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/octopress-logo.png 200 &amp;lsquo;Octopress Logo&amp;rsquo; %}
I am not sure why I never noticed or found it sooner (as I am sure I
have heard of Octopress before!) &amp;ndash; but I finally stumbled across the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org&#34;&gt;Octopress site&lt;/a&gt;. Octopress is a framework
designed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://brandonmathis.com&#34;&gt;Brandon Mathis&lt;/a&gt; for Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had finally found the toolset I was looking for!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Octopress had plenty of themes, still stuck to Jekyll as the method of generating static
sites &amp;ndash; and had plugins which smoothed over some of the &amp;lsquo;warts&amp;rsquo; of
Jekyll out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some of the static blog-generating goodness (i.e. integrations) you will find in
Octopress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disqus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delicious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook likes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The configuration file in a &amp;lsquo;stock&amp;rsquo; Octopress install is a nice YAML
layout. Here is a snippet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;``` yaml _config.yml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_4:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;main-configs:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;Main Configs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_6:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;url: &lt;a href=&#34;http://yourblogurl.com&#34;&gt;http://yourblogurl.com&lt;/a&gt;
title: Your Blog Name
subtitle: Some catchy subtitle..
author: Your Name Here
simple_search: &lt;a href=&#34;http://google.com/search&#34;&gt;http://google.com/search&lt;/a&gt;
description: This will show in the META tags
```&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making changes is as easy as changing the appropriate key/value
pair and then from the terminal, run: &lt;code&gt;rake preview&lt;/code&gt; to view it on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:4000&#34;&gt;http://localhost:4000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deploying the site is just as easy:
&lt;code&gt;bash
rake generate   #generate the static site content
rake deploy     #deploy the site to your deploy location (i.e. github)
&lt;/code&gt;
You can even abbreviate deployment to: &lt;code&gt;rake gen_deploy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Octopress also has plenty of themes as a starting point for customizing your own blog.
The github repo &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/imathis/octopress/wiki/3rd-Party-Octopress-Themes&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is a good starting point for 3rd party Octopress themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now (&lt;em&gt;for the time being&lt;/em&gt;) sold on Octopress and will be using it for
my posts going forward. If you are in the market for a new static
blogging platform, give it a try &amp;ndash; I think you will be pleasantly
surprised.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refining your tech talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-01-10-refining-your-tech-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-01-10-refining-your-tech-talk/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shaking-off-the-rust:0b079ec9875d52687a2f6c6364aa59cd&#34;&gt;Shaking off the rust&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img left /images/hanselman.jpg Scott Hanselman %}
Last night I did the first tech talk (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rabbitmq.com/&#34;&gt;RabbitMQ&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://easynetq.com/&#34;&gt;EasyNetQ&lt;/a&gt;) that I have done in at least a one or two years at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hrnug.org/&#34;&gt;Hampton Roads .NET Users Group (HRNUG)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to have respect for my audience when giving these talks and work
provide them with something that is entertaining as well as
educational. I wouldn’t want my time wasted with a bad presentation – so I don’t want to waste the audience’s time either! In giving my talks, I strive to emulate the great tech speakers and educators like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.8thlight.com/our-team/robert-martin&#34;&gt;‘Uncle Bob’ Martin&lt;/a&gt;.
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wekeroad.com/&#34;&gt;Rob Connery&lt;/a&gt; does a great interview of Scott Hanselman in his Full Throttle series on Tekpub on &lt;a href=&#34;http://tekpub.com/productions/ft_speaker&#34;&gt;how Scott prepares for a tech talk&lt;/a&gt;. If you are serious about giving tech talks, I highly recommend you look at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-learned:0b079ec9875d52687a2f6c6364aa59cd&#34;&gt;What I learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech talks can through you some curve-balls that; if you are willing to pay attention, can provide some teachable moments that you can use to refine future tech talks. I found my teachable moments in a couple of areas while giving the presentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure to use your phone or watch as a timer – to help you keep the ‘pace’ through your tech talk. Setting it to the max talk time and having it count down will work – or have a half way point set and check to see where you are in the total presentation I was allotted 60 – 75 minutes, but my talk came in at around 45 minutes because I though I was running out of time. These extra minutes could have been used to dive deeper into my code examples!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t been playing with PowerPoint lately, &lt;a href=&#34;http://presentationsoft.about.com/od/powerpoint101/ss/shortcuts.htm&#34;&gt;brush up on the start (F5) / restart (SHIFT-F5) keystrokes&lt;/a&gt;. When you are in the middle of a presentation, it can disrupt the flow of the talk when you have to forward to the last slide you where one. I rehearsed my talk, except I didn’t rehearse switching into my demos. While F5 will start a slideshow in Power Point, it always starts at the beginning. In the middle of the talk, I couldn’t remember what the restart keystroke was, so I had to forward from the beginning slide each time I stopped for a demo. This can be a little choppy for the viewers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you use any other tools, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/bb897434.aspx&#34;&gt;ZoomIt&lt;/a&gt; – make sure you set their key mappings to what you want them to be and make sure you practice using it in your talk rehearsal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately I get a do-over next month with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://757rb.org/&#34;&gt;757 Ruby Users Group&lt;/a&gt;. I have some tweaking to do to the presentation in order to tailor it for a slightly different audience, but the changes are really just the demos and substituting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ruby-amqp/amqp&#34;&gt;amqp gem&lt;/a&gt; for EasyNetQ. But my lessons learned on the presentation flow will definitely be incorporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img center /images/unclebob.jpg Uncle Bob Martin %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure there will be many more of these teachable moments in the future…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global day of Coderetreat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-12-09-global-day-of-coderetreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-12-09-global-day-of-coderetreat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I participated in my first
&lt;a href=&#34;http://coderetreat.org&#34;&gt;coderetreat&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.757creativespace.com&#34;&gt;757 Creative Space&lt;/a&gt; in Norfolk, VA.
 This happened to be the &lt;a href=&#34;http://globalday.coderetreat.org/&#34;&gt;Global day of Coderetreat&lt;/a&gt; (which was organized by coderetreat.org) and now I am wondering why I didn’t go to a coderetreat sooner.
The coderetreat was facilitated by &lt;a href=&#34;http://myfakeif.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan
Castillo&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://757rb.org&#34;&gt;757Ruby users group&lt;/a&gt; and sponsored by some great companies: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bootstraphero.com&#34;&gt;Bootstrap
Hero&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xtuple.com/&#34;&gt;xTuple&lt;/a&gt; sponsored all of the good eats (which are essential to keep the code flowing!) and there were quite a few other great sponsors as well.
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-code-retreat:e5427fa611f5a49cf659ce5cae569ae1&#34;&gt;What is a code retreat?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img left /images/IMG_1509.jpg 184 244 %}
If you haven’t been to a coderetreat – it basically a day of honing your software development skills to become a better developer.
If you are serious about your profession as a software developer – these
types of training opportunities are ones you should attend. In our day’s
retreat, we focused on the skills of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test-driven_development&#34;&gt;TDD&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremeprogramming.org/rules/pair.html&#34;&gt;Pair Programming&lt;/a&gt;.
Both of these techniques are part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.extremeprogramming.org/index.html&#34;&gt;Extreme Programming&lt;/a&gt;.
The idea for coderetreat was spawned at the January, 2009, Codemash
Conference by Gary Bernhardt, Patrick Welsh, Nayan Hajratwala and Corey
Haines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-day-s-activities:e5427fa611f5a49cf659ce5cae569ae1&#34;&gt;The day&amp;rsquo;s activities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/IMG_1510.jpg 244 184 %}
The only project used for the day is to code a version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_game_of_life&#34;&gt;Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game
of Life&lt;/a&gt;.
Now, I knew a little about the Game of Life and that it was typically central to a coderetreat, but I purposefully did not look up any info on coding it, because I didn’t want it to take away from the discovery experience.
Programmers are typically paired for 45 minutes and each pair has to delete all code and destroy all notes at the end of their iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan did a great job of getting everyone introduced and oriented. Once we had all of the intros under our belt, we paired up and started on our first iteration of the Game of Life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;along-came-the-curve-balls:e5427fa611f5a49cf659ce5cae569ae1&#34;&gt;Along came the curve-balls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the curve-balls: requirements changing during the iterations, ping-pong coding (switching the person typing and observing between writing functions), blind coding (the 2 programmers couldn’t talk, and one wrote the tests – the other the code to pass the test) and timed coding from test to implementation.
{% img left /images/IMG_1512.jpg 244 184 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these “curve-balls” built on the other and exposed some of the typical flaws in the way most people write software as well as the things that can be done to fix it.
After each 45 minute iteration we held a sort of “after action review” to see what each person had learned from the iteration.
These iterations brought out the importance of writing clear function/method/variable names, writing your tests first, and doing the simplest thing possible to pass the test, then moving to the next item.
It is amazing to see how quickly this technique of TDD can flush out an excellent design for any software project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-retrospective:e5427fa611f5a49cf659ce5cae569ae1&#34;&gt;The retrospective&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day ended in a wrap-up review of all of the items during the day from iteration – to see what we had learned, what were surprised by, and what we would change.
Everyone seemed to have picked up something constructive from the experience – so the coderetreat was in my opinion a big success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan was a great facilitator for the event – he nudged us into seeing the ‘teachable moments’ during the iterations.
Meeting all of the great developers there was also a great part of the experience.
We had programmers coding in Java, C#, Ruby, Python, JavaScript, and even Objective-C. Everyone was willing to work with others, even in languages they were not quite familiar with.
 We even had a pair of developers that came down from Richmond to attend the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the next coderetreat!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>