<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/miscellaneous/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/miscellaneous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>From WordPress to Octopress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-06-02-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-06-02-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/wordpress_to_octopress.png 440 &amp;lsquo;Wordpress to Octopress&amp;rsquo; %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may or may not have noticed this blog has switched from a
hosted &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordpress.org&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; blog to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; blog.
I originally started looking at migrating the blog for a couple of
reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love ruby and I wanted to play around with &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jekyll can be deployed easily to &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github Pages is free (as in like free beer&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The amount of comment spam I am getting on WordPress was driving me
crazy (yes I know I can use Akismet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to customize my blog a little more than what is allowed
with WordPress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-initial-search:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;The initial search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially I started looking at some of the blogging tools that my
friends at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://757rb.org&#34;&gt;Hampton Roads Ruby Users Group&lt;/a&gt; where using.
The first one I came across that caught my interest was &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/metaskills&#34;&gt;Ken Collins&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://metaskills.net&#34;&gt;metaskills.net&lt;/a&gt;.
The metaskills blog uses a modified version of Jekyll which Ken has added in a few items to organize and publish easier.
You can check out his code &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/metaskills/metaskills.net&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-draft-jekyll:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;First draft: Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/octojekyll.png 200 &amp;lsquo;OctoJekyll&amp;rsquo; %}
I started out creating a plain Jekyll blog and looking at how the static
site generation worked.
There are plenty of resources on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll site&lt;/a&gt; which can show you how to install Jekyll and get it running.
You will need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-lang.org&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rubygems.org&#34;&gt;RubyGems&lt;/a&gt;.
If you are dabbling in Ruby or Rails, you will already have both of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;second-draft-jekyll-bootstrap:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;Second draft: Jekyll Bootstrap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img left /images/Jekyll-bootstrap-screen.png 300 &amp;lsquo;Jekyll Bootstrap Getting Started screen&amp;rsquo; %}
While I found Jekyll pretty cool, I wanted my site to have a little bit
of styling.
Not being a graphic designer of any sort, I started looking for some
themes that I could use to modify.
After doing a little digging on Google for Jekyll themes, I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllbootstrap.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; by
X. Note: There is also another spin off from this project called
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ruhoh.com&#34;&gt;Ruhoh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-draft-octopress:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;Final draft: Octopress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/octopress-logo.png 200 &amp;lsquo;Octopress Logo&amp;rsquo; %}
I am not sure why I never noticed or found it sooner (as I am sure I
have heard of Octopress before!) &amp;ndash; but I finally stumbled across the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org&#34;&gt;Octopress site&lt;/a&gt;. Octopress is a framework
designed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://brandonmathis.com&#34;&gt;Brandon Mathis&lt;/a&gt; for Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had finally found the toolset I was looking for!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Octopress had plenty of themes, still stuck to Jekyll as the method of generating static
sites &amp;ndash; and had plugins which smoothed over some of the &amp;lsquo;warts&amp;rsquo; of
Jekyll out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some of the static blog-generating goodness (i.e. integrations) you will find in
Octopress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disqus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delicious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook likes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The configuration file in a &amp;lsquo;stock&amp;rsquo; Octopress install is a nice YAML
layout. Here is a snippet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;``` yaml _config.yml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_4:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;main-configs:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;Main Configs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_6:df86dc409d528fdc365321b82b0da9f6&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;url: &lt;a href=&#34;http://yourblogurl.com&#34;&gt;http://yourblogurl.com&lt;/a&gt;
title: Your Blog Name
subtitle: Some catchy subtitle..
author: Your Name Here
simple_search: &lt;a href=&#34;http://google.com/search&#34;&gt;http://google.com/search&lt;/a&gt;
description: This will show in the META tags
```&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making changes is as easy as changing the appropriate key/value
pair and then from the terminal, run: &lt;code&gt;rake preview&lt;/code&gt; to view it on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:4000&#34;&gt;http://localhost:4000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deploying the site is just as easy:
&lt;code&gt;bash
rake generate   #generate the static site content
rake deploy     #deploy the site to your deploy location (i.e. github)
&lt;/code&gt;
You can even abbreviate deployment to: &lt;code&gt;rake gen_deploy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Octopress also has plenty of themes as a starting point for customizing your own blog.
The github repo &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/imathis/octopress/wiki/3rd-Party-Octopress-Themes&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is a good starting point for 3rd party Octopress themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now (&lt;em&gt;for the time being&lt;/em&gt;) sold on Octopress and will be using it for
my posts going forward. If you are in the market for a new static
blogging platform, give it a try &amp;ndash; I think you will be pleasantly
surprised.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batteries Included</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-04-05-batteries-included/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-04-05-batteries-included/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I usually use a desktop PC and my Macbook Air on a daily basis during the week. In going back and forth between Windows and Mac OS X, I have noticed a couple of things that have hammered home the point that hardware is not the only thing Apple does well &amp;ndash; software is too.
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;
{% img left /images/password_protect_files_snowleopard.jpg 350 Save as PDF on Mac %}
The first thing that occurred to me is Mac OS X has had the ability to print and edit PDF files at least since Mac OS X Leopard. With Windows, I need to download some type of PDF print driver and an Adobe viewer. Mac OS X has preview (which works for both images and PDF files), which will let me view and do some light editing on a PDF file as wells annotate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/notification-center.jpg Mac OS Notification Center %}
The second thing I noticed was Mac OS X Lions notifications center provides not only a nice area to see your email and app notifications, but also an easy way to post to Twitter and Facebook. Growl notification is baked in as well &amp;ndash; I have to download a growl client for windows (and the app has to use Growl).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not quite sure why Windows doesn&amp;rsquo;t have &amp;ldquo;batteries included&amp;rdquo; when it comes to PDF files, but it is just a nice feature that Apple has added into Mac OS X. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: I have used Windows for a long time &amp;ndash; and I was a Windows user before I used a Mac. Windows gets a lot of things right and I will continue to use Windows as well &amp;ndash; but Apple seems to be getting very good at sanding down the &amp;ldquo;friction points&amp;rdquo; you encounter with software to make for an easier, elegant user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes its just nice for things to work as you intend them to and to serendipitously find some functionality that is often overlooked&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-11-18-diy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-11-18-diy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well today was a productive day: I changed the rear brake pads and rotors for my car today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img left /images/car_repair_8bit.jpg 325 %}
Yes, I know this is not as great an automotive accomplishment as rebuilding an engine. However, I find something innately satisfying with getting your hands dirty and figuring out how to do something you normally don&amp;rsquo;t do. I have always enjoyed figuring out how to fix things and perhaps that is what drew me into computers and software.
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;
I believe we have a lot of technology (cars being one of them) that most of us use and take for granted. When this technology needs to be maintained/repaired many of us lack the knowledge to do so. My personal goal to counter this lack of &amp;lsquo;automotive know-how&amp;rsquo; is to fix whatever can on my car, whenever I can &amp;ndash; and hopefully save money in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the resources I have found helpful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreillyauto.com/&#34;&gt;O&amp;rsquo;Reilly auto parts&lt;/a&gt; - my favorite auto parts store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.haynes.com/mole-video&#34;&gt;Haynes Manuals Online&lt;/a&gt; - a must have for DIY auto repair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>