<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rants on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/rants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rants on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/rants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Batteries Included</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-04-05-batteries-included/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013-04-05-batteries-included/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I usually use a desktop PC and my Macbook Air on a daily basis during the week. In going back and forth between Windows and Mac OS X, I have noticed a couple of things that have hammered home the point that hardware is not the only thing Apple does well &amp;ndash; software is too.
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;
{% img left /images/password_protect_files_snowleopard.jpg 350 Save as PDF on Mac %}
The first thing that occurred to me is Mac OS X has had the ability to print and edit PDF files at least since Mac OS X Leopard. With Windows, I need to download some type of PDF print driver and an Adobe viewer. Mac OS X has preview (which works for both images and PDF files), which will let me view and do some light editing on a PDF file as wells annotate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/notification-center.jpg Mac OS Notification Center %}
The second thing I noticed was Mac OS X Lions notifications center provides not only a nice area to see your email and app notifications, but also an easy way to post to Twitter and Facebook. Growl notification is baked in as well &amp;ndash; I have to download a growl client for windows (and the app has to use Growl).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not quite sure why Windows doesn&amp;rsquo;t have &amp;ldquo;batteries included&amp;rdquo; when it comes to PDF files, but it is just a nice feature that Apple has added into Mac OS X. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: I have used Windows for a long time &amp;ndash; and I was a Windows user before I used a Mac. Windows gets a lot of things right and I will continue to use Windows as well &amp;ndash; but Apple seems to be getting very good at sanding down the &amp;ldquo;friction points&amp;rdquo; you encounter with software to make for an easier, elegant user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes its just nice for things to work as you intend them to and to serendipitously find some functionality that is often overlooked&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing updates 4 of 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-11-19-installing-updates-4-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-11-19-installing-updates-4-of-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;{% img right /images/please_wait.jpg 325 &amp;lsquo;Installing updates 4 of 6&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Installing updates 4 of 6&amp;rsquo; %}
OK: I like Windows 8 so far. I think it is a pretty good OS. My only gripe with it so far is that lately it has been stalling on the updates. The screen will say something to the effect of &amp;ldquo;Do not power down&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Installing update 4 of 6&amp;rdquo;. It will do this for several hours&amp;hellip;with occasional hard disk activity. Eventually I have to pull the battery on my laptop to restart it. I am thinking: Really??&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>