<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mechanic on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mechanic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mechanic on Switchspan: Hindsight is an exact science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mechanic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-11-18-diy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2012-11-18-diy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well today was a productive day: I changed the rear brake pads and rotors for my car today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img left /images/car_repair_8bit.jpg 325 %}
Yes, I know this is not as great an automotive accomplishment as rebuilding an engine. However, I find something innately satisfying with getting your hands dirty and figuring out how to do something you normally don&amp;rsquo;t do. I have always enjoyed figuring out how to fix things and perhaps that is what drew me into computers and software.
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;
I believe we have a lot of technology (cars being one of them) that most of us use and take for granted. When this technology needs to be maintained/repaired many of us lack the knowledge to do so. My personal goal to counter this lack of &amp;lsquo;automotive know-how&amp;rsquo; is to fix whatever can on my car, whenever I can &amp;ndash; and hopefully save money in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the resources I have found helpful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreillyauto.com/&#34;&gt;O&amp;rsquo;Reilly auto parts&lt;/a&gt; - my favorite auto parts store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.haynes.com/mole-video&#34;&gt;Haynes Manuals Online&lt;/a&gt; - a must have for DIY auto repair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>